Hello
everyone, and welcome to another episode of Trust Talks.
Health insurance is a must.
But the problem is the high premium.   We receive
many inquiries asking if we can provide information on health insurance plans that are affordable for the average person on a limited budget.
So today we are discussing a comparison of five
budget-friendly health insurance
plans available in the market today
.  One is Tata AG
Health Insurance Company's Medicare
Select, two is ICC Lopard's
Elevit, three is Manipal Cigna Health
Insurance Company's Sarva Uttam, four is
Nivaboba Company's Aspire and Anach Star
Health Insurance Company's
Super Star Health Insurance Company's Health Insurance About the
Company's USP of this Plan
Eligibility Criteria In-
Built Benefit and Optional Riders Vetty Parade
and Most Important Premium
of this Plan If you want
to understand things like this, don't miss this video and
try to watch it in full.
Before entering the video, a
quick introduction about myself.
My name is Sanojalal, a certified financial
consultant. I have been working in the insurance and investment industry for the past 19 years.
We bring all the news related to insurance to you only after studying and researching it very authentically. If
you have not yet subscribed to this channel called Trust Talk,
please.  Subscribe to the
channel to get the right information about Arabi
Healthy and Wealthy
First Point About the Company Tata
AG and ICICI Lombard are general
insurance companies, meaning that these two companies market not only health insurance
plans but all general insurance
plans. The
other three companies Manipal,
Cigna, Niva, Buba and Car Health are
stand-alone health insurance companies,
meaning that
these three companies market only health insurance plans.
Now let us understand the ICR of these five companies.
Before this, what is ICR? ICR indicates the ratio of how much an insurance
company has paid out as insurance claims out of the total premium collected during a year.
ICR indicates that insurance companies that maintain an ICR
between 60 percent and 80 percent can be
considered insurance companies with a good claim settlement track record. Tata AG Health
Insurance Company's ICR is 77.94%
ICC Lopad  78.85
Manipal Signa E 63.78
Niva Boba Itz 59.02
An Star Health Insurance ICR 66.47
Osa Now let us understand the top three USPs of these five companies. The
first USP that is common in all four of the five plans today is Infinity Sum
Insured or Infinite Insurance Coverage,
that is, if
a huge claim comes in a hospitalization claim outside the Sum Insured,
this coverage is
available through this feature. In Medicare Select, this
feature is known as Infinite
Advantage. In Elevate Plan, it is called Infinity
Care. In Putham Plan, it is
Anant Aspire.
This option is not available at the moment. In
Super Star Plan, it is called
Unlimited Care. To give an example, the
base sum insured of my plan is Rs.
10 lakh.  But if the hospital
expenses are Rs 50 lakh, then this
feature provides insurance cover for this.
This feature is available in all four plans.
This option is only
available once in the entire policy life. There
is a slight difference in this. Although this
feature is available every year, this feature works out only for
four conditions such as critical conditions, heart-related issues, cancer, stroke, major organ and bone marrow transplantation. The second important thing is that USB is
early access to Tata AIG's Medicare Select. If the
customer opts for a
multi-year policy instead of a single-year policy,
that is, if instead of a one-year
premium, he pays two or
three years' premium together, the
cumulative amount for three years can be used by
the customer at any time during the policy year.
For example, if the sum insured is 10 lakhs, the customer can use this feature at any time during the policy year.  If
you take a year policy, then if the
customer gets a claim in the first year itself, if a claim of Rs
30 lakh is made,
the customer gets coverage for this through this feature.
The second
important USB of ICICI Elevate is Unlimited Sum
Insured. This is a very simple
feature. You can decide the sum insured limit you want. If the
customer wants a higher sum
insured coverage of 5 Crosses or
CR,
you can apply for it through this feature.
Next USB
is the surplus benefit of Sarva Uttam plan. This
feature offers double
protection coverage.
Sum plus one more additional sum
is added on for the first claim reported in every policy year. For example, a  The
individual
gets the lax coverage on the first claim itself. Next up is the Common USB with Nivabuba
Aspire and Star Health's Super
Star plan. Lock
the premium means that the customer only has to pay the same premium that is paid when joining the policy
every year until a claim occurs during the policy life
.  For example, if a
10-lacs sum insured is paid at the age of 25 at Rs. 18,000,
the
same premium of Rs. 18,000 will be
paid to the customer at the age of 45.
This means that the age
base premium does not increase until a claim is made.
Next, the third USP common to all five plans
is the loyalty
bonus, or the guaranteed cumulative bonus that the policyholder receives at the time of renewal
.  In the Medicare Selector
plan, this feature is known
as the Super Charge Bonus.  Through this feature, the
customer gets 100% guaranteed addition sum assured. For
sum assured up to 5 lakhs, three times of sum
assured and for sum assured up to 10 lakhs, five
times of sum assured are
given as bonus. In the plan called Next ICC
Elevate, this feature is
known as Power Booster. Every year, just
like Tata, 100% of
sum assured is added as a guaranteed bonus to the
customer, that too for
unlimited time. For example, a
person who takes a sum assured of 10 lakhs,
10 lakhs is added on to
the customer for every renewal, guaranteed for
unlimited time. Next Sarva
Uttam Planning This feature is known as
GUK. Same feature Guaranteed
Cumulative Bonus Upto  100% sum
assured is added on every year, but
here only the maximum add-on
is given in the form of a feature called Booster in Next Aspire.
Through this feature, the
unused sum assured or sum
insured is carried forward to the customer every
year.
This feature in Next Super Star plan is
known as Super Star
Bonus. Just like the Power Boost in Elevate plan,
100%
guaranteed cumulative bonus is
added on every year for unlimited time. So far,
we have discussed the
important features of these five plans.
Now let
us quickly understand the eligibility criteria to join this plan.
First, the policy type is Individual as well as Floater option in all the
five plans.
The customer
can choose the Next Point
Family Definition.  The floater option is
available for Aptusa members up to Medicare Select plan for up to two
adults plus three children. In all
Uttam plans, the floater option is available for Aptusa
members, Asp Adults Plus for
Children, Super Star
Adults Plus for Children, and Next Option. The age of
entry is
18 years for adults in all five plans, and the maximum age of entry is
unlimited times.
Only in Aspire plan, the age of entry is
limited to 65 years for adults. The age of entry for children is
9 years old in all plans. The maximum age
of entry in the children
category is 25 in Medical Select and Elevate and Uttam plans, and again it is
25 in Aspire and Super Stan plans. Next Point Sum  Insured is up
to Rs 5 lakh crore in Medical Selector plan, up to Rs
5 lakh crore in Elevate, up to Rs
5 lakh crore in Sarva Uttam plan, up to Rs 5
lakh crore in Asper plan, up to Rs 3 lakh crore in Super
Star plan, and up to Rs 5 lakh crore in the
next policy term. In all policies, there is a facility to opt for multi-year payment time. This is from one year to three years. The customer can choose all the plans. In Elevate plan, it is up to five years policy. Next, let us
understand the basic in-built features of these five plans. The first
point is room rent. In all
four plans, a single
privacy room comes by default in the plan except the
Super Star
plan, which has an extra room.  The category is
Next Point Pre and
Post Hospice,
Tata Medicare Select It is 90
or 90 days, while the other four plans are 90 and
180 days. Pre and post
hospitalization is Next
Points Ayush Expenses Ayurveda Yoga Unani Siddha
Homeopathy Expenses Donor
Expenses Domiciliary Hospitalization
Day Care Procedures and Modern
Treatment Robotic i.e.
robotic surgery expenses
etc. The
customer gets coverage up to sum inshod in all these five plans.
Next Point
is Unlimited Restoration Benefit,
i.e. in case the base sum inshod is
exhausted by the customer,
an additional sum inshod is added to the customer's next claim.
Restoration is a benefit that is added to the customer's next claim.  The five
plans and the restoration
benefit option for it are available in these five plans. The
next point
is ambulance coverage, the expenses of which are
covered in these five plans.
Next is the inbuilt no claim
bonus. In the Medical Selected plan, it is
offered every year at 50% up to 100% for every claim free year. In the
Elevate plan, it is 20% year on year up to
100%, in the Sarva Uttam plan and
Aspire, the no
claim bonus option is not available. In the
Next Super Star plan, it
is 50% no claim inbuilt
up to 100% for every claim
free. Next, the
optional riders of these five plans, that is, the
features or
features that the customer needs are purchased by paying an extra premium. Let
us
understand what these are. The first optional rider is
consumables.  Or Non Medical
Expenses This option rider
is available in all plans. The
insurance cover for this is available to
the customer up to the sum insured as a claim. The
next point
is the pre-existing disease waiting period. For
existing diseases such as ABCD, asthma,
diabetes, hypertension, etc., the
waiting period is normally three years. If that waiting
period is reduced by days,
this pre-existing disease
waiting period
reduction is an option that is currently available in the Elevate plan,
Manipal Cigna's Uttam plan, and
Super Star plan.
This option is not available in Tata and Nivabo's Aspire. The
next point
is Infinity Coverage, an infinite insurance
review. We have already discussed
Infinity Advantage
Infinity Care. We have discussed all these options
first as key USBs.
Next is an
important optional rider. Loyalty
Bonus Guaranteed Accumulative Bonus.
These are the options available in all our five plans.
This is also a
key benefit that we have already discussed.
Next is an important
option. Maternity. In all these five
plans,
we can choose the maternity option as an optional rider. Next, let
us understand the waiting periods of these five plans. First
point: In all these five plans, the initial
waiting period is 30 days. Next Specified
Illness waiting period is the same for
two years in all plans.
Pre-existing disease waiting period also remains the same for three years. Next waiting period
is maternity. In Medical Select plan, the
waiting period is two years.
We have one year.
The option to reduce is available.  Again, the same
option is available in the Elevate
plan, which also reduces the
maternity waiting period to one year next year. In the Sarva Uttam plan, the waiting period is the same. In the Aspire plan, the maternity waiting period is four years,
two years, or months. Depending on the
plan
variant we choose,
we can change the maternity waiting period. In the
Super
Star plan, the maternity waiting
period is two years.  So far, we have understood all the
inbuilt features, optional
riders, eligibility criteria,
waiting period, etc. of this plan.
Now,
let's take a look at the most important premium of these plans to see if this is a budget-friendly plan.
Here is the age illustration: If
a family of 32-29 years chooses a sum
insured of 10 lakhs in a floater policy, without any
optional
riders, the premium of Medicare Select is
13638, in
Elevate Plan it is 1550, in
Sarva Uttam Plan the premium is 1292, in
Asper Plan the premium is 15520
and in Super Star Plan the premium is
118. We hope that the
detailed comparison of the budget-friendly health insurance plans that we have discussed today has been
useful for you. We have discussed only the most important features of
these plans, which have many features and facilities. If
you have any doubts about these plans and need a personal consultation,
you can feel free to
call or text on the number provided.
Before the video ends, a
reminder: Insurance  Is a subject
matter of solicitation? Before choosing any insurance
product or plan,
read and understand the terms and conditions of that product clearly.
Similarly, if
you have not yet subscribed to the informative channel called Trustok,
please
subscribe to the channel to get the right information at the right time. I am
coming with another informative video, I am signing of Sanoj Lal
[Music]